

# SIDDHARTH GARG

Developer, AI Engineer, CFA - Passed level 1

- @ i@siddharthgarg.in
- Hyderabad, India | Remote (Preferred)
- in https://www.linkedin.com/in/sidg510/

## **EDUCATION**

Btech, Computer Science | VIT Vellore (Institute of **Eminence**)

- **=** 07/2018 06/2022
- Vellore, India
- CGPA: 9.07

12th Grade, All India Senior School Certificate Examination(AISSCE) | Delhi Public School, RK Puram

- **1** 07 2015 05 2017
- New Delhi, India
- Score: 90%

10th Grade, All India Secondary School Certificate (AISSC) | Delhi Public School, Agra

- **2015**
- New Delhi, India
- CGPA: 9.4

## TECH STACK

## **Programming**

Python SQL **JavaScript** Java

#### AI/ML

**CNNs Sentiment Analysis** Image Recognition **Object Detection** 

**Topic Modeling RNNs** 

# Web Development

PHP Django Flask **NodeJS** ReactJS

#### **UI/UX**

Photoshop Illustrator Canva Adobe XD

## CERTIFICATIONS



Cleared Level 1 of Chartered Financial Analyst (CFA) Examination

**TensorFlow Developer Certificate** 

Google's TensorFlow Developer Certificate

Skydiving

Tandem Skydiving Certificate, Pattaya

Consecutive First Prize, RCPC 2020 and 2019 Coding Competition, involving several rounds by ACM, VIT

## **ABOUT ME**

Started learning to write code when I was 12 years old, there was no going back from there. I enjoy my work, let it be Tech, Design or Finance, I love exploring different disciplines and developing solutions, that create value. Love to travel, been to (almost) everywhere in the country.

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### Member Tech | DE Shaw India

**a** Jan 2022 – 5 Mar 2024 (LWD)

Acquired in-depth Finance and Technical knowledge in Fundamental equities team. Developed a framework from scratch for validating and reporting insights from multiple alternative data sources, reducing time from 1hr to

#### Intern Member Tech | DE Shaw India

**May 2021 - July 2021** 

Remote (Hyderabad Office)

Developed an extendible python application for tracking different internal tools' performance. Worked with Elastic, Logstash, Influx and Kibana.

#### Computer Vision Engineer | FindMind Analytics

Feb 2020 - Nov 2020

Programmed a high accuracy end to end pipeline with a REST API for OCR and masking of clients' sensitive documents using object detection, increasing speed 30x and accuracy to 97% from 60%

#### Marketing Head, Vellore Executive Board & Volunteer | ERIDE (NGO)

**Sep 2018 - Dec 2020** 

Vellore, India

Empowering Rural India with Digital Education(ERIDE) aims on delivering digital literacy tounderprivileged people. Joined as a freshman, from teaching kids in orphanages, communitycentres to leading the NGO as a board member

Creative Head | Mozilla Firefox Club VIT

**Sep 2019 - Dec 2020** 

Vellore, India

Oversaw the club's activities, mentored designers, guided junior members in technical projects.

Senior Core Committee Member, Tech | Computer Society of India, VIT

Dec 2018 - Dec 2019

Vellore, India

Organized hackathons, lead workshops and programmed CTFs, with amazingly talented people I was fortunate enough to work with them on projects exposing students to new concepts.

### **PROJECTS**

Malware Family classification using Convolutional Neural Networks on Byte Sequences | •

GUI based End to End Auto ML dashboard for object detection and masking. | Ownership transferred to FindMind Analytics

REST API for OCR and masking of sensitive data in Identity documents using image processing and object detection | Ownership transferred to FindMind **Analytics** 

Sentiment Analysis and Topic Modelling of primetime News-hourDebates from different news channels | •

TB Saathi (Tuberculosis Diagnosis using neural networks tool) | # | 2nd Prize in Hello World Hack